tommyclarke.com 2016-11-04

# Privacy Policy - Tommy Clarke - Tom Clarke

_Last updated: 3 January 2015_

Tom Clarke® (“TC”) is dedicated to providing an informative and useful website on and through the domain names TomClarke.me, TommyClarke.com, TommyKnife.com and/or other domain names designated by TC from time to time (the “Website”). As a part of the operation of the Website, TC gathers certain information about users. This Privacy Policy applies to the Website and governs data collection and usage at the Website. Please, read this Privacy Policy carefully. By accessing or otherwise using the Website, you signify your assent to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, you are not permitted to access or otherwise use the Website.

**Data Collected**

Two types of data are collected: (a) personal data, such as names, company names, postal addresses, e-mail addresses, telephone numbers, credit card account information, financial institution account information, age, gender, and product and service preferences (“Personal Data”); and (b) non-personal aggregate or traffic data, such as your IP address, which web pages are being visited, the order in which the web pages are being visited, which hyperlinks are being “clicked”, how many users are visiting the Website, domain server, type of computer and type of web browser (“Traffic Data” and together with Personal Data, the “Collected Data”).

**Collection and Usage**

Personal Data is gathered when users provide Personal Data to or through the Website, for example, when registering with the Website or purchasing any TC product or service through the Website or entering any of the Website’s contests, sweepstakes or promotions (“Promotions”).

Traffic Data is tracked and gathered when you and other users visit the Website. While gathering Traffic Data may not collect Personal Data, it may provide information on the geographical location from which users access the site. This Traffic Data generally does not identify individual users. Instead, the Traffic Data identifies Website users as a whole, including demographic information, preferences in content and advertising, quality of service, and web traffic patterns.

Collected Data may be released to persons and/or entities affiliated or contracted with TC (“Affiliates”) (including, without limitation, strategic alliances and advertising affiliated persons and/or entities). For instance, Personal Data may be used to: (1) send you information about TC and our products, services, special offers, Promotions and/or upcoming events; (2) send you information about Affiliates’ products and services; (3) conduct surveys about your opinion of TC, its staff, performance, products and services or the Website; (4) verify your qualifications for certain promotions, special offers, products and services; (5) bill you for any products and services purchased through the Website via a credit card or electronic payment; and (6) customize and tailor your experience on the Website by displaying content that TC thinks you might be interested in according to your preferences. You consent to the release of your Collected Data to Affiliates of TC.

Collected Data may also be released to any persons and/or entities not affiliated or contracted with TC (“Non-Affiliate”) directly associated with your instructions, requests, reservations and/or registrations for products or services provided by TC or Non-Affiliate (including, without limitation, customer support, information technology support, credit card or other electronic payment processing and personal profile services) when the transfer of such Collected Data is necessary to provide you with such products or services. By instructing, requesting, reserving and/or registering for such products or services through the Website from TC or Non-Affiliate, you consent to the release of your Collected Data to Non-Affiliate. TC shall use reasonable efforts to provide the Non-Affiliate access only to the Personal Data necessary to assist in responding to your instructions, requests, reservations and/or registrations for such products or services and cause such Non-Affiliate to use your Personal Data for these limited purposes.

In the event that TC sells, buys, merges or otherwise reorganizes, all or a controlling part of, TC’ assets and/or equity, your Collected Data may be released, transferred, sold or otherwise conveyed (“Conveyed”) to prospective or actual buyers, sellers or persons and/or entities merging with TC. You consent to any and all such Conveyances of your Collected Data.

The names of Promotion winners and participants may be used in connection with Promotions. Names and other Collected Data may also be released to the sponsors of Promotions for the sponsors’ use in connection with the Promotion. By entering a Promotion, you consent to the release of your Collected Data to the Promotion sponsor or as otherwise allowed in accordance with the Promotion rules.

Please note that chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups may be available through the Website. Any information disclosed in these areas is or may be deemed to be public information and you must exercise caution and discretion when deciding to disclose personal and non-personal information.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose Personal Data or personally sensitive data through your home page, linked sites, or other public forums, this information may be collected and used by others. TC encourages all users to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to from the Website so that you understand how those websites collect, use and share information about you and/or your computer. TC is not responsible for the data collection, data usage, privacy statements or content on other websites.

TC generally does not disclose any user information to third parties other than identified in this Privacy Policy. TC will, however, disclose Personal Data, Traffic Data or non-personal data without notice, if requested to do so by any law enforcement agency or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on TC; (b) protect and defend TC’s rights or property; and (c) to protect the personal safety of the Website’s users, TC employees or the public.

**Opt Out**

In the event that TC wishes to transfer or release your Personal Data to a third person in a manner not set forth in this Privacy Policy, TC shall inform you prior to such transfer or release and provide you with the ability to opt out of such transfer or release of Personal Data.

**Cookies**

The Website may place small files, called ‘cookies’ onto your computer. Cookies are data files that websites write onto computer hard drives for record keeping purposes when you visit them. The cookie file then identifies you as a unique user. As a convenience feature, cookies simplify the process of recording personal information, so that, for example, users do not have to enter names, addresses or passwords repetitively. Cookies also allow users or TC to customize some sites features.

You can program your browser not to accept cookies, but if you do, you may be unable to access some parts of the Website, and the Website will not be able to customize features according to certain preferences.

While on the Website, you may receive cookies from third party advertisers or promotional entities. These cookies are outside the control of TC, are not subject to the Privacy Policy, and TC is not responsible for such third party cookies.

**Measures to Safeguard Children**

TC encourages parents and guardians to spend time with their children online and to be fully familiar with the websites visited by their children. At various places on the Website, TC may ask users whether they are 18 years of age or older. TC relies on users to be truthful in responding to these questions.

TC does not intentionally gather or solicit Personal Data from or about children under 18 years of age. A parent or guardian whose child provided Personal Data to TC without the parent’s or guardian’s consent should immediately notify TC of such disclosure in writing to the contact provided below. TC, upon receipt of such written notice, shall take reasonable measures to remove such disclosed information from TC’s database.

**Security**

TC has implemented security measures to help protect your Personal Data. For example, TC stores Personal Data on secured servers and transmits Personal Data through secure and encrypted channels. Although TC has implemented such security measures to help protect your Personal Data, your Personal Data may still be accessed, altered, disclosed and/or otherwise used in an unauthorized manner and as such, TC is not responsible if such unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure and/or other uses occur.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

TC will occasionally update this Privacy Policy to reflect company and user feedback, or changes in applicable law. You are encouraged to periodically review this Privacy Policy to be informed of how TC utilizes or discloses user information. Your continued use of the Website constitutes your consent to any and all such changes.

**Governing Law/Claims**

Nevada law governs this Privacy Policy, the Website, and any claim associated with, related to, or arising from the Privacy Policy and/or Website. Any claim associated with, relating to, or arising from this Privacy Policy or the Website shall be brought in a federal or state court in Las Vegas, Nevada within one year after the claim arises. Users of the Website consent to the sole and exclusive jurisdiction of courts located in Las Vegas, Nevada as the most convenient and appropriate for the resolution of disputes concerning this Privacy Policy. The Website is controlled, operated and administered entirely within the United States. Use of the Website from locations outside the United States where these practices are illegal or violate any law is prohibited.

**Contact Information**

Questions about this Privacy Policy should be directed to the contact page on this site.

Tom Clarke ® is a Register Trademark with the USPTO and may only be used with permission.
